A little blessing in disguise.
The Fall is a adventure, fantasy, drama film directed by Tarsem Singh.
In a hospital on the outskirts of 1920s Los Angeles, an injured stuntman begins to tell a fellow
patient, a little girl with a broken arm, a fantastic story about 5 mythical heroes.
Thanks to his fractured state of mind and her vivid imagination, the line
between fiction and reality starts to blur as the tale advances.
Roy Walker, played by Lee Pace.
Nurse Evelyn / Sister Evelyn, played by Justine Waddell.
Sinclair / Governor Odious, played by Daniel Caltagirone.
Darwin / Orderly, played by Leo Bill.
Walt Purdy, played by Sean Gilder.
Mystic / Orange Picker, played by Julian Bleach.
The Fall is a 2006 adventure fantasy film produced, co-written, and directed by
Tarsem Singh, and starring Lee Pace, Catinca Untaru, and Justine Waddell.
It is based on the 1981 Bulgarian film Yo Ho Ho written by
Valeri Petrov and directed by Zako Heskiya.
The film centers on a young girl (Untaru) who meets a stuntman (Pace) at the hospital they are both staying at, with
the latter telling her a fantastic tale involving a group of heroes seeking revenge on an evil ruler.
Presented by David Fincher and Spike Jonze, the film premiered at the 2006 Toronto International Film Festival,
before being released in the United States on 9 May 2008, and the United Kingdom on 3 October 2008.
In the years since its release, the film had become noteworthy for its lack of distribution and absence from any
streaming platforms, with Singh having worked to find distributors to re-release the film worldwide.
In July 2024, streaming service Mubi announced their acquisition of select distribution rights to a 4K restoration of
the film, which premiered at the Locarno Film Festival before streaming on Mubi on 27 September 2024.
The film explores themes of suicide attempt,
stuntman, remake, morphine, hospital.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting and emotional.